marshill.com 2014-11-02

# Privacy Policy | Mars Hill Church

Mars Hill Church ( **"Mars Hill"** ) recognizes that your privacy is very important to you and that you have a right to control your personal information. We acknowledge that when you provide personal information about yourself to another party it is an act of trust. In response, Mars Hill takes the process of upholding an individual's privacy very seriously.

Mars Hill Church (“Mars Hill”) owns and/or maintains the following websites:

  * Mars Hill ([marshill.com](https://marshill.com/))
  * Resurgence ([theresurgence.com](http://theresurgence.com/))
  * Connect Desk ([theconnectdesk.com](https://theconnectdesk.com/))
  * Pastor Mark ([pastormark.tv](http://pastormark.tv/))
  * Mars Hill Church on The City ([marshill.onthecity.org](https://marshill.onthecity.org/))
  * Mars Hill Church YouTube Channel ([youtube.com/user/mhcseattle](https://youtube.com/user/mhcseattle))
  * Resurgence YouTube Channel ([youtube.com/user/theResurgence](https://www.youtube.com/user/theResurgence))

These websites are collectively referred to as the “Site”, which this Privacy Policy applies to.

Unless you give Mars Hill explicit consent to act otherwise, the following policy will govern how Mars Hill handles your personal information and safeguards your privacy.

By using any Site, you are giving us your express consent to use all the information that we collect about you in the manner described in this policy. This includes the release of such information to owners of each respective Site and third parties as described below.

##  Collection and Use of Personal Information

Mars Hill collects two different types of information. One type is voluntary information, which you provide, such as registration information for events, membership information, or shipping and billing information. The other type of information Mars Hill collects is user information provided by your computer each time you visit this site, such as Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or browser. The information that Mars Hill collects helps us to provide information and service to you. We may combine information from other sources with the information that we collect.

Any information that you provide to Mars Hill or that is obtained through the Site may be used by Mars Hill or the respective owners of the Site. While Mars Hill will not sell, rent or lease your personal information to commercial entities, we may provide your information to third parties with whom we have a relationship to offer you products and services we believe may be of interest to you.

Mars Hill may offer services to you such as chat rooms, message boards, or other similar discussion forums. Please be aware that any information you divulge in these arenas is deemed public information and is not protected.

##  Cookies and Other Technologies

The Sites, online services, interactive applications, email messages, and advertisements may use “cookies” and other technologies such as pixel tags and web beacons. A cookie is a small file or part of a file stored on a World Wide Web user's computer, created and subsequently read by a web site server, and containing personal information (as a user identification code, customized preferences, or a record of pages visited). These technologies help us better understand user behavior, tell us which parts of the Site people have visited, and facilitate and measure the effectiveness of advertisements and web searches. We treat information collected by cookies and other technologies as non-personal information. However, to the extent that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local law, we also treat these identifiers as personal information. Similarly, to the extent that non-personal information is combined with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

Mars Hill also uses cookies and other technologies to remember personal information when you use the Site, online services, and applications. Our goal in these cases is to make your experience while on the Site more convenient and personal. We do not use cookies to obtain any personal information about you before or after you leave the Site. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can reset your browser to either refuse all cookies or to notify you when you are receiving a cookie and allow you to decide whether or not to accept it.

As is true of most websites, we gather some information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type and language, Internet service provider (ISP), referring and exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information to understand and analyze trends, to administer the Site, to learn about user behavior on the Site, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Mars Hill may use this information in our marketing and advertising services.

Pixel tags enable us to send email messages in a format customers can read, and they tell us whether mail has been opened. We may use this information to reduce or eliminate messages sent to customers.

##  Links to other sites

As a courtesy, Mars Hill may provide links to other sites that are neither owned nor controlled by Mars Hill. Some of these sites may use the Mars Hill or Resurgence logo. These third party sites, however, are NOT subject to or bound by this Privacy Policy. Such third party sites may or may not have their own privacy policies and may or may not collect personal information from you or place cookies on your browser. Mars Hill is not responsible for the privacy policies or any information collection practices of these sites or any damages resulting therefrom.

##  Service Providers

Mars Hill shares personal information with companies who provide services such as information processing, managing and enhancing customer data, providing customer service and conducting customer research or satisfaction surveys. These companies are obligated to protect your information.

##  Others

It may be necessary − by law, legal process, litigation, and/or requests from public and governmental authorities within or outside your country of residence − for Mars Hill to disclose your personal information. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that for purposes of national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary or appropriate.

We may also disclose information about you if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our terms and conditions or protect our mission, our operations, or our users. Additionally, in the event of a transfer, reorganization, merger, or sale of the website, we may transfer any and all personal information we collect to the relevant third party.

##  Protection of Personal Information

Mars Hill takes precautions — including administrative, technical, and physical measures — to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft, and misuse, as well as against unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.

Mars Hill uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption on all web pages where financial information is collected. When making donations to Mars Hill or purchasing any products sold through our websites, you must use an SSL-enabled browser such as Safari, Firefox, or Internet Explorer. Doing so protects the confidentiality of your personal information while it’s transmitted over the Internet.

When you use some Mars Hill services or applications or post on a Mars Hill forum, chat room, or social networking service, the personal information you share is visible to other users and can be read, collected, or used by them. You are responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these instances.

##  Integrity and Retention of Personal Information

Mars Hill makes it easy for you to keep your personal information accurate, complete, and up to date. We will retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

##  Access to Personal Information

You can help ensure that your contact information and preferences are accurate, complete, and up to date by logging in to your account at marshill.com and updating your information and preferences.

##  Children

Mars Hill encourages parents and guardians to spend time with their children online. No information may be submitted to or posted on Mars Hill's web site by users 13 years old and younger. Unless otherwise disclosed during collection, Mars Hill will not provide any personally identifying information, regardless of its source, to any third party for any purpose whatsoever for our users 13 years and younger. If any services or features on the site require registration, a user 13 years old and younger will be required to provide the email of the parent or guardian which will allow us to notify that person that the child has registered for a service or feature. Parental or guardian consent will consist of an email from that person to Mars Hill stating that they are aware that the child is using the web site. Identifying a website user as 13 or under is not easy and Mars Hill will not be held responsible for anyone misrepresenting themselves as over 13 when in fact they are not.

##  Updates and amendments to the Privacy Policy

Mars Hill reserves the right, at its sole discretion, to change, modify, add or remove portions of this Privacy Policy, at any time. It is your responsibility to check this Privacy Policy periodically for changes. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes will mean that you accept and agree to the changes.

##  Questions or Concerns

If you have questions or concerns about this privacy policy, please contact our Legal Team at: legal@marshill.com.

The information contained in this web site is subject to change without notice.
